Federico Holc

portfolio.fedeholc.ar · github.com/fedeholc · linkedin.com/in/federicoholc federicoholc@gmail.com · +54-11-2394-8988 · Buenos Aires, Argentina



About me

Hi! I'm Fede, a full stack web developer specialized in frontend, with a strong foundation in backend technologies and a keen interest in web standards and open-source software. I began my journey as a self-taught developer and am now on the verge of graduating as a software development technician. Previously, I worked as a sociologist and taught at middle schools and the University of Buenos Aires. In my portfolio, you'll find the projects I've worked on (along with their code), as well as explanations of the challenges I faced and the lessons I learned from each experience.

Summary of qualifications

My skills and technical knowledge include:

- HTML / CSS / Responsive design
- Vanilla JavaScript / React / Next.js
- TypeScript / JSDoc
- Linux

- Testing (Vitest/Jest, Playwright)
- Node.js / Express
- SQL / MongoDB
- Git / GitHub

In aditión, my experience have allowed me to develop the following skills:

- Working with agile methodologies (Scrum / Kanban).
- Teamwork
- Effective communication
- Initiative / autonomy

- Time management / responsibility
- Problem solving
- Active listening / empathy
- Attention to detail

Education

- **Higher Technician Degree in Software Development.** Technical Training Institute No. 29 of the Autonomous City of Buenos Aires. 2023 to present (18 subjects of 23 approved).
- **Higher Education Specialist in Comprehensive Sexual Education.** Dr. Joaquín V. González Higher Institute of Teaching. 2017 –2019. Graduated.
- **Professor of Secondary, Normal and Special Education in Sociology.** Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Buenos Aires. 2007 2009. Graduated.
- **Bachelor's Degree in Sociology.** Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Buenos Aires. Buenos Aires. 2002 2007. Graduated.
- **Computer Technician.** Technical School N° 3 Maria Sánchez de Thompson, Autonomous City of Buenos Aires. 1992 1998. Graduated.

Courses

- AWS Academy Cloud Foundations, AWS Academy, 2024.
- **Full Stack Web Developer. Argentina Program v3.0,** National Institute of Industrial Technology (INTI), Ministry of Economy of the Nation, 2022-2023.
- Codo a Codo 4.0 Full Stack JAVA, Ministry of Education of the Autonomous City of Buenos Aires, 2022.
- Responsive Web Design / JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures / Back End
 Development and APIs, freeCodeCamp.org, 2022.

Languages

- Spanish: native.
- **English:** professional working proficiency. First Certificate Exam (B2 First), Cambridge University.

Work Experience

Web Developer. No Country, work simulation internship. Oct. - Nov., 2024.

 Team development of the telemedicine application Health Pro. Individually I was in charge of developing the video call and waiting room modules of the application, using React, Node, WebSockets and WebRTC.

High school teacher. 2010 - to present.

- Teacher of Sociology, History, Introduction to Social Sciences and Humanities, and Ethics and Citizenship Education in public high schools in the Autonomous City of Buenos Aires.

Professor and university tutor. University of Buenos Aires. 2007 - 2015.

- Professor of Introduction to Scientific Thinking, Common Basic Cycle, Marqués Chair (2007-2011). Professor and tutor of Teaching Practices. Faculty of Social Sciences, Pipkin Chair (2009-2015).

Sociologist, Environmental Health Department, Ministry of Health of the Government of the Autonomous City of Buenos Aires. 2008 - 2012.

 Development and implementation of instruments for the survey of environmental problems in the Health and Community Action Centers in Buenos Aires. Training of personnel in their use. Analysis of socio-environmental data using Epi Info, MS Access databases, and SPSS.

Software development projects

JWT Learning Kit - Roll your own auth, at least once in your life

- JWT Learning Kit is a guide to learn how to develop from scratch an authentication system in JavaScript using JSON Web Token. It includes the code and the explanation of the processes and concepts necessary for its implementation.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, vanilla JavaScript, Node, Express, SQLite, Vitest, Playwright, JSDoc.
- Online: jwtlk.fedeholc.ar

fotoYOP & foto-V

- FotoYOP allows you to transform images and create collages simply and quickly. It is also a PWA that can be installed on the phone and used offline. Foto-V is your ideal complement: it converts images into videos by applying effects such as panning or zoom in/out.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, vanilla JavaScript, React/Next, TypeScript, JSDoc, PWA, Canvas API.
- Online: fotoyop.fedeholc.ar · foto-v.fedeholc.ar

Health Pro - Telemedicine application

- Health Pro is a telemedicine application developed as a team as part of a work simulation by No Country. I was in charge of developing the video call and waiting room modules of the application.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, WebSockets, WebRTC.
- Repo: https://github.com/No-Country-simulation/c21-m-15-java-react

<NuncaSupeProgramar/> Blog of notes for learning web development

- My blog to organize notes, learn, and share knowledge. Simple, fast, and accessible
- Stack: Next, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Markdown.
- Online: <u>nsp.fedeholc.ar</u>

¡ANOTÁ! & Highlighter - ¿Another note taking app?

- That's right, yet another note-taking application =) But with some particular special features. And the best: a browser extension that allows you to highlight and save texts and links from any web.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Next, SQLite, WebExtension API.
- Live demo: <u>anota-demo.vercel.app</u>

Full size images for IG

- Extension for Chrome browser that allows you to view Instagram images at full resolution and in full screen, without distractions.
- Stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, WebExtension API.
- Disponible en la chrome web store: bit.ly/igfull +2000 users.

Other projects:

- Web application for the administration of an educational institution (course project). Stack: MongoDB, Node, Pug, JavaScript, Vitest, JWT, HTML, CSS.
- Desktop application to manage a health clinic (course project). Stack: C#, Visual Studio,
 MySQL.
- Mobile application to manage a sports club (course project). Stack: Kotlin, Android Studio,
 SQLite.
- Argentina Programa v3.0 Editable resume (course project). Stack: Java, Springboot, Hibernate, MySQL, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.

